Eamon Grennan papers, 1964-2010
Emory University
- Printed material, 1943-2010, Series 5; Boxes 76 - 80
  - 2000 April 16, East End Poetry Workshop, Southampton, New York (Box 78, Folder 40)
  - 2000 May 6, Finnegans Awake, Consulate of Ireland, San Francisco, and Irish Arts Foundation, San Francisco, California (Box 78, Folder 41)
  - 2000 September 23, Poetry Reading: How Do I Love Thee?, Second Annual Fall for the Book, The Washington Post, Fairfax, Virginia (Box 78, Folder 42)
  - 2000 September 29, Eamon Grennan Poet, Washington College, Chesterfield, Maryland (Box 78, Folder 43)
  - 2000 October 13, Eamon Grennan and Colum McCann, The Fund for Irish Studies at Princeton University, Princeton, New Jersey (Box 78, Folder 44)
  - 2000 October 16, Poetry reading with Eamon Grennan, Creative Writing Program, English Department, and College of Arts and Sciences Cultural Committee at Suffolk University, Boston, Massachusetts (Box 78, Folder 45)
  - 2000 October 25, Theatre of Ideas Poets on Poets, Miller Theatre at Columbia University, New York, New York (Box 78, Folder 46)
  - 2001 March 7, Harp Speech, Poets-in-Public Series, International Poetry Forum, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania (Box 78, Folder 47)
  - 2001 March 18, Distinguished Poets Series, Claverack Free Library, Claverack, New York (Box 78, Folder 48)
  - 2001 April 24, Cúirt Internaional Festival of Literature, Galway Arts Centre, Galway, Ireland (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - 2002 April 5, The Reynolds Writers and Readers Series, University of Nebraska Kearney, Kearney, Nebraska (Box 79, Folder 2)
  - 2002 April 18, "An Irish Poet in America," Second Annual Franklin A. Steele Guest Faculty Community Forum, Chestnut Hill Academy, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - 2002 April 19, BardFest, BerksBards, University Park, Pennsylvania (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - 2002 September 23, 75th Anniversary of the Grolier Poetry Book Shop, Poetry Society of America, Cambridge, Massachusetts (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - 2002 October 24, Writers Harvest Reading, New York University Graduate Creative Writing Program, New York, New York (Box 79, Folder 6)
  - 2002 October, Eamon Grennan Acclaimed Irish Poet, Brockport Writers Forum of the Department of English and Schools of Letters and Sciences at Suny College at Brockport, Brockport, New York (Box 79, Folder 7)
  - 2002 November 4, "The Best of Westchester 2002," Creative Arts Café Poetry Series, Northern Westchester Center for the Arts, Mt. Kisco, New York (Box 79, Folder 8)
  - 2002 November 15, Parents' Night Out, Oakwood Friends School, Poughkeepsie, New York (Box 79, Folder 9)
  - 2003, January 27, W.B. Yeats: The Man and the Muse, a Celebration of the Irish Laureate's Poems and Persona, W.B. Yeats Society of New York, New York, New York (Box 79, Folder 10)
  - 2003 March 21, International Poetry Festival, Dun Laoghaire-Rathdown County Council and the Arts Council of Ireland, Dun Laoghaire, Ireland (Box 79, Folder 11)
  - 2003 March 27, Greyfrair Living Literature Series, Siena College, Loudenville, New York (Box 79, Folder 12)
  - 2003 April 23, Eamon Grennan Poet, Sophie Kerr Committee, O'Neil Literary House, and the Mainstay, Rock Hall, Maryland (Box 79, Folder 13)
  - 2003 September 21, Master Class Poetry: Eamon Grennan and Alice Quinn, New Yorker Festival, New York, New York (Box 79, Folder 14)
  - 2003 October 4, Meet the Writers Literary Series, Manhattanville College's Dowd/O'Gorman Writing Center and the Master of the Arts in Writing Program, Purchase, New York (Box 79, Folder 15)
  - 2004 March 1, Irish Arts 2004, Folger Poetry 03/04, Folger Shakespeare Library, Washington, D.C. (Box 79, Folder 16)
  - 2004 April 28, Spring Convocation, Convocation Address "The Call," Vassar College, Poughkeepsie, New York (Box 79, Folder 17)
  - 2004 May 3, Eamon Grennan, New York State Writers Institute at the University of Albany, Albany, New York (Box 79, Folder 18)
  - 2004 May 6, Verse Writing, Vassar College, Poughkeepsie, New York (Box 79, Folder 19)
  - 2004 May 11 and 25, Advanced Poetry Workshop, Hudson Valley Writers' Center, Sleepy Hallow, New York (Box 79, Folder 20)
  - 2005 November 8, Poetry Reading by Eamon Grennan, Graduate Student Association, Irish Studies, and the Department of English at Catholic University of America, Washington, D.C. (Box 79, Folder 21)
  - 2006 March 17, Poetry Reading by Eamon Grennan honoring the late Michael J. Durkan, Swarthmore College English Department, Swarthmore College Library, and Friends of Lester Conner, Swarthmore, Pennsylvania (Box 79, Folder 22)
  - 2007 February 21, Lamont Poetry Program, Phillip Exeter Academy, Exeter, New Hampshire (Box 79, Folder 23)
  - 2007 May 6, Meet the Writers Literary Series, Masters of Arts in Writing Program and Dowd/O'Gorman Writing Center at Manhattanville College, Purchase, New York (Box 79, Folder 24)
  - 2007 May 16, MacDowell's Colony 100th Anniversary, Poetry Society of America, MacDowell Colony, and Hunter College Masters of Fine Arts in Creative Writing Program, New York, New York (Box 79, Folder 25)
  - 2008 February 13, Readings and Conversations, Lannan Foundation, Santa Fe, New Mexico (Box 79, Folder 26)
  - 2008 February 21, Alice Quinn: Twenty Years of Poetry at The New Yorker, Academy of American Poets, The New School Graduate Writing Program, Poets House, and Poetry Society of America, New York, New York (Box 79, Folder 27)
  - 2008 October 28, 131st Residency, Atlantic Center for the Arts, New Smyrna, Florida (Box 79, Folder 28)
  - 2009 February 11, Walt Whitman Tribute Evening, Readings and Conversations, Lannan Foundatin, Santa Fe, New Mexico (Box 79, Folder 29)
  - 2009 April 16, Vassar College Bookstore, Author Series, Vassar, College, Poughkeepsie, New York (Box 79, Folder 30)
  - 2009 May 18, Annual Folger Poetry Board Reading, Folger Shakespeare Library, Washington, District of Columbia (Box 79, Folder 31)
  - 2009 October 14, Evening of Poetry, Nicholas Roerich Museum, New York, New York (Box 79, Folder 32)
  - 2010 March 5, Wallace Stevens, New York, and Modernism in honor of John N. Serio, Wallace Stevens Journal, New York, New York (Box 79, Folder 33)
  - Other printed material
  - Brochure, A Joycean Jaunt: A Detailed Tour of Joyce's Dublin, no date (Box 79, Folder 34)
  - Clippings, general, no date (Box 79, Folder 35)
  - Clippings, Ireland, 1943-1972 (Box 79, Folder 36)
  - Clippings, Irish poets and writers, no date (Box 79, Folder 37)
  - Clippings, James Joyce, no date (Box 79, Folder 38)
  - Clippings, "Poems in Transit" [original arrangement by Grennan], 1980 (Box 79, Folder 39)
  - Clippings, translation, no date (Box 79, Folder 40)
  - Essay, "Coleridgean Names" by Robert DeMaria, Jr. Journal of English and Germanic Philology, July 1978 [Includes inscription from DeMaria to Grennan] (Box 79, Folder 41)
  - Essay, "The Critical Theory of James Joyce" by Haskell M. Block, The Journal of Aesthetics an Art Criticism, March 1950 (Box 79, Folder 42)
  - Essay, "La Lingua Inglese in Irlanda: Considerazioni sulla sua storia e sulle sue Caratteristiche Interne" by Máire McHugh Barisone, Annali della Facoltá di Scienze Politiche, 1980-1982 [Includes inscription from Barisone to Grennan] (Box 79, Folder 43)
  - Essay, "The Martyr Clown: Oscar Wilder in De Produndis" by Joesph Butwin, The Victorian Newsletter, Fall 1972 [Includes inscription from Butwin to Eamon and Joan Grennan] (Box 79, Folder 44)
  - Essay, "Melville's Search for the Primitive" by William Heath, Dialectical Anthropology, 1978 (Box 79, Folder 45)
  - Essay, "The Sense of the Sleight-of-Hand Man" by Dana Gioia, Hudson Review, 1984 [Includes inscription from Gioia to Grennan] (Box 79, Folder 46)
  - Essay, "Sophocles and the Poets" by David Young, Field, Spring 2006 [Includes reference to Oedipus at Colonus, translated by Grennan] (Box 79, Folder 47)
  - Essay, "'The Thinker as Reader': The Figure of the Reading in the Writing of Wallace Stevens" by Robert DeMaria, Jr., Genre, 1979 [Includes inscription from DeMaria to Grennan] (Box 79, Folder 48)
  - Etching by Steven Trefonides, 1976 [Includes inscription from Trefonides to Grennan] (Box 79, Folder 49)
  - Map, Ulysses map of Dublin, 1963 (Box 79, Folder 50)
  - Minich, Anne, exhibition at Bowdoin College Museum of Art, Brunswick, Maine, 1992 [Includes image of painting, Eamon at the Front] (Box 79, Folder 51)
  - Open Place, number 26 [Includes "Heady Weather," "The Given," "Fox," "On the Train Home," and "In the National Library" by Grennan], Fall/Winter 1978 (Box 79, Folder 52)
  - Ploughshares, volume 2, number 3 [Includes "The Chilean Singer" by Grennan] (Box 79, Folder 53)
  - Poems by others: Fallon, Peter, "Caesarian," Broadside, March 1984 [Includes inscription from Fallon to Grennan] (Box 79, Folder 54)
  - Poems by others: Fallon, Peter, "The Blaskets," 2001 [Includes inscription from Fallon to Grennan] (Box 79, Folder 55)
  - Poems by others: Fallon, Peter, "The Witches Corner," Broadsides, 1986 [Includes inscription from Fallon to Grennan] (Box 79, Folder 56)
  - Poems by others: Gioia, Dana, "Eastern Standard Time," "His Three Women," and "Parts of Summer Weather," The Hudson Review, autumn 1984 [Includes inscription from Gioia to Grennan] (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - Poems by others: Montale, Eugenio, "Eugenio Montale: Four Poems" translated by Harry Thomas, Literary Imagination: The Review of the Association of Literary Scholars and Critics, 2000 [Includes inscription from Thomas to Grennan] (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - Poems by others: Muldoon, Paul, "Horace: Book III Ode XVIII," December 2001 [Includes inscription from Muldoon] (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - Poems by others: O'Neil, Chuck, "River Millwork," published in The Recorder, Summer 2007 [Includes inscription from O'Neil to Grennan] (Box 80, Folder 4)
  - Poems by others: various authors, no date (Box 80, Folder 5)
  - Poetry, volume CLXI, number 4, January 1993 (Box 80, Folder 6)
  - Program for Columbia Composers, Fourth Concert of 1991-1992 season, featuring the Mosaic Ensemble, March 1992 [Includes "Source," "Skunk," "Vespers," and "Laundromat" by Grennan] (Box 80, Folder 7)
  - Program for Sophocles' Oedipus at Colonus translated by Eamon Grennan and Rachel Kitzinger, performed by the Handcart Ensemble, New York, New York (Box 80, Folder 8)
  - Program for Special Awards and Commendations Ceremony featuring Kate Grennan, June 1986 (Box 80, Folder 9)
  - Program for Vassar College, Department of Music, Music Faculty Recital, September 2009 [Includes "Swifts over Dublin by Grennan"] (Box 80, Folder 10)
  - Readings and appearances by others, 1995-2003 (Box 80, Folder 11)
  - Review, "Among the New Poetry" by Tom Clark, review of "Still Life and Other Poems" by Julian Bell, San Francisco Chronicle, September 1987 (Box 80, Folder 12)
  - Review, "Jackals in Paradise" by Eric Ormsby, review of Eugenio Montale Collected Poems 1920-1954: Ossi di sepia/Cuttlefish Bones, Le occasioni/The Occasions, La Bufera e altro/The Storm, Etc. translated and annotated by Jonathan Galassi, Parnassus: Poems in Review, January 2000 (Box 80, Folder 13)
  - Translations by Grennan, "Chorus from Oedipus at Colonus" by Sophocles, St. Ann's Review, Winter/Spring 2004 (Box 80, Folder 14)
  - Translations by Grennan, "The Coastguard House" and "To My Mother" by Eugenio Montale, Columbia, 2002 (Box 80, Folder 15)
  - Translations by Grennan, "Colonus Chorus" by Sophocles, Poetry Ireland Review, Spring 2002 (Box 80, Folder 16)
  - Translations by Grennan, "Early Evening: A Zen Moment" by Nuala Ní Dhomhnaill, TriQuarterly, Spring 2002 (Box 80, Folder 17)
  - Translations by Grennan, "My Trojan Horse" by Nuala Ní Dhómhnaill, Recorder, Spring/Fall 1997 (Box 80, Folder 18)
  - Translations by Grennan, "Oedipus to Theseus" by Sophocles, St. Ann's Review, Winter/Spring 2004 (Box 80, Folder 19)
  - Translations by Grennan, "To the Moon" by Giacomo Leopardi, no date (Box 80, Folder 20)
- Photographs, 1963-1989, Series 6; Box 81
  The series consists of photographs of Grennan's travels, as well as a slide of a painting of Eamon Grennan by artist Anne Minich.
  - Deadman Cove, unidentified, undated (Box 81, Folder 1)
  - Eamon at the Front by Anne Minich, 1988-1989 (Box 81, Folder 2)
  - Europe, 1963-1964 (Box 81, Folder 3)